# Chibuike E. Ugwu

Curriculum Vitae

School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Washington State University Pullman, WA, USA

Website : chibuikeugwu.github.io Email **≤**: chibuike.ugwu@wsu.edu

# RESEARCH SUMMARY

My general research interests are in Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML), with a main focus on developing robust, safe, and trustworthy ML algorithms for addressing critical real-world challenges within safety-sensitive domains. My current work focuses on developing efficient algorithms and theoretical frameworks to enhance the reliability and safety of deep learning **algorithms**. My research is specifically concentrated on:

- Adapting Uncertainty Quantification methods, like Conformal Prediction, to facilitate effective and secure human-ML collaboration within healthcare applications.
- Trustworthy Out-of-Distribution (OOD) Detection for ensuring the reliability of ML models when applied to real-world tasks beyond their original training scope.

# **EDUCATION**

Ph.D., Computer Science Washington State University	$2022-{ m Present} \ Pullman, \ WA, \ USA$
Advisor: Prof. Jana Doppa	
BS., Statistics (First Class Honors)	2014-2018
University of Nigeria	$Nsukka,\ Nigeria$
Thesis title: Sensitivity of Randomization test and F-test in Some Experim	nental Designs
Class rank: Best Graduating Student	
Professional Appointments	

Research Assistant EECS Department - Washington State University	Aug 2022 – Present Pullman, WA, USA
Teaching Assistant  EECS Department - Washington State University  - CptS 223: Advanced Data Structures C/C++ (Fall-2022)  - CptS 315: Introduction to Data Mining (Spring-2023)  - CptS 223: Advanced Data Structures C/C++ (Fall-2023)  - CptS 315: Introduction to Data Mining (Spring-2024)	Aug 2022 – Present Pullman, WA, USA
Teaching Assistant Statistics Department – Kano State Polytechnic	$2019-2020 \ Kano,\ Nigeria$

## AWA

Statistics Department Rand State I digitaline	mano, myena
VARDS AND HONORS	
♥ Outstanding Graduate Teaching Assistant in EECS Award, VCEA Voiland College of Engineering, Washington State University	2024
<b>▼ EducationUSA Opportunity Fund Program Scholar</b> USA Embassy, Abuja, Nigeria	2022
<b>P</b> Best Graduating Student         Statistics Department − University of Nigeria	2018
<b>♥ Winner: Nigerian Statistical Association (NSA) competition</b> Representative of the University of Nigeria.	2018
<b>♥</b> Gold medalist: NSA competition individual category Representative of the University of Nigeria.	2018

1 of 2 Chibuike E. Ugwu Curriculum Vitae

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## Papers Under Review and Preprints

- 1. [AAAI'25] Chibuike E. Ugwu, Yan Yan, Diane Cook, Janardhan Rao Doppa. Adaptive Prediction Regions for Multi-target Regression. AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), (Under Review).
- 2. [DATE'25], Pratyush Dhingra, Chibuike E. Ugwu, Jana Doppa and Partha Pratim Pande. ERGo: Energy-Efficient Hybrid GNN Training on Heterogeneous Processing-In-Memory Architecture. Proceedings of ACM/IEEE Design, Automation and Test in Europe Conference (DATE), (Under Review).
- 3. Chibuike E. Ugwu, Yan Yan, Diane Cook, Janardhan Rao Doppa. Importance-Weighted Calibrated Region Prediction of Multi-target Cognitive Health Measures from Smartwatch Sensor Data. ACM Transactions on Computing for Healthcare (Under Review).

#### JOURNAL PAPERS

1. Oladugba, A. V., **Chibuike E. Ugwu**, & Onwuamaeze, U. C. (2023). Sensitivity and robustness of randomization test and F-test in some experimental designs. *Quality and Reliability Engineering International*, 39(7), 2967-2974.

#### Conference Papers

1. Oladugba, A. V., **Chibuike E. Ugwu**, & Onwuamaeze, U. C. (2018). A Comparison of randomization test and F-test in some experimental designs.

Nigerian Statistical Association 42nd Annual National Statistical Association conference, 2018.